Daniel Shaw

Full Stack Developer | Software Engineer

**** 07590841741

danielshaw71@gmail.com

https://github.com/Daniel Shaw98

London

PROJECTS

Insite

Currently designing and building an e-learning course marketplace MVP.

- · Designing frontend and components with Figma.
- Building with Ruby on Rails, Stimulus JS, PostgreSQL, HTML and SCSS.
- · Using the Devise gem for authentication.

Website Portfolio

Developed a self-designed portfolio website using Figma for design, and built with React, Vite, and CSS for a responsive and modern user interface.

- Showcasing my projects, including Insite, Vloyal and Supper Club.
- · https://danielshaw.pro

Vloyal

Vloyal was created to turn paper loyalty cards into virtual loyalty cards storing them in one app, using a QR code scanner to add virtual stamps.

- · Acted as the project lead and project manager.
- · Managed all merges and resolved all conflicts in GitHub.
- · Implemented the QR code scanning feature to the web app.
- Worked on multiple animations using JavaScript.
- Used Figma and CSS to add styling throughout the web app.
- Presented and showcased the final product to 100+ people.

Supper Club

Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of Airbnb called 'Supper Club'. The web app enabled users to create and showcase their supper club events, as well as to discover and buy tickets to other supper clubs.

· Lead and managed this week-long project.

EXPERIENCE

Venue Finding DesignMyNight

= 2022 - 2023

Demonstrated clear effective communication and consistent fast response times, operating as the intermediary between clients and venues. I converted 12 sales within 8 weeks. Attended multiple networking events, developing client management and networking skills.

Events Sales Manager

Fortem International

=== 2022

Held a client-facing role researching and connecting with new businesses to build a portfolio of clients for global trade shows run by Fortem International. Developed skills in sales, business development and client relationship management.

Property & Land Agent

Ideal Land

m 2019 - 2021

Bought in £7M worth of property deals between 2020-2021. Managed the office and day to day business, including setting up and updating the website, and building the Company LinkedIn profile from 200 to 1,300 followers within a year. My responsibilities included;

- Leading searches for land and properties, monitoring and updating the databases.
- Drawing up contracts for deals including NDA's, Retention letters and Heads of Terms.
- Building relationships with new and current clients, as well as networking with industry professionals.
- Arranging GDPR and AML training for the company and managing the continued use of these practices.

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-shaw-ds98/

SUMMARY

Over the past year I have pursued my career ambition to become a Full Stack Developer. This began through Codecademy supplemented by Free Code Camp and YouTube. I joined the Le Wagon Web Development Course in October and graduated as a Full Stack Developer. I worked 2 jobs part-time throughout spring and summer to help fund the course, whilst continuing to learn to code/programming.

SKILLS

Web Application Development

Problem Solving		Teamwork	Organisation
React	Ruby	Ruby On Rails	JavaScript
HTML CSS		SQL Git/V	ersion Control
Heroku	Figma	GitHub	Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Web Development

Le Wagon

= 2023

- 9-week full-time intensive web development bootcamp, accredited by BCS.
- Learned and used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SQL, Git, GitHub, Figma, Heroku and Ruby/Ruby on Rails
- Conceptual learning included OOP, MVC, APIs and Version Control.

Business Entrepreneurship University of the West of England

= 2017 - 2018

- Completed year 1 achieving a 2.1.
- Received ILM: Level 3 Award in Leadership & Management.

A-Levels

Emanuel School

= 2014 - 2016

 Mathematics, Economics, Business Studies & Geography.

CERTIFICATION

Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Completed a certification course for Ruby, JavaScript, HTML and CSS provided by Codecademy.